# **Nick Pelletier**

- Montréal, QC
- github.com/nwpelletier

- (438) 680-1479
- in linkedin.com/in/nwpelletier
- https://nwpelletier.github.io/

# **Objective**

Curious and creative developer driven by a love of problem-solving and thoughtful design. I focus on web technologies and enjoy crafting clean, intuitive experiences. Always learning, I aim to build solutions that are both functional and meaningful.

# **Professional Experience**

# **Software and Web Developer**

**CERASP** 

01/2024 - present | Montreal, QC

- Developing a React-based website using Strapi as a headless CMS to allow easy content generation for the user, and lightweight responsive design across devices.
- Worked on Unity VR projects, contributing to the development and optimization of interaction simulations.

# **Sound Recording Technician**

McGill University

01/2020 - 01/2022 | Montreal, QC

- Assisted in recording and production of high-quality audio for various projects and events.
- Operated studio equipment and collaborated with faculty and students to achieve project goals.

#### **Production Assistant**

Industrial Light & Magic (ILM)

08/2016 - 08/2018 | Vancouver, BC

- Assisted in the production of visual effects for major film projects, handling support tasks in a fast-paced environment.
- Gained experience in project coordination and creative collaboration.

# **Skills**

#### **Web Development**

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node.js

# **Development Tools and Task Management**

Git, Postman, AWS, Trello, Notion, Jira, Figma

#### **Game Development**

Unity, C#, FMOD

# **Education**

# **AEC, Full Stack Development**

John Abbott College 01/2023 – 01/2024 | Montreal, QC

#### **Master, Sound Recording**

McGill University
09/2019 – 04/2021 | Montreal, QC

#### **Bachelor**, Music

University of Ottawa 09/2009 – 04/2013 | Ottawa, ON

#### **Projects**

#### Whisper Ads (Google Chrome Extension)

- Developed a Chrome plugin to subdue or mute autoplay video/ad volume.
- Used JavaScript and Chrome API for seamless extension creation.

# **Procedural Map Generator (Unity)**

Ongoing Personal Project

- Built a random map generation system for games using Kruskal's algorithm to ensure fully connected, programmed in C#.
- Designed for modular 3D environments with roombased structures, supporting replayability and dynamic level design.